The Princess Sapphire
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Princess Knight,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
First Episode
The Princess Knight
- Another exercise! Now!
- Yes, right away, Prince!
Here you go!
Admirable!
All five on target!
But not in the center, though.
Well, I will try again.
Here goes!
You hit the center,
this time!
No! The arrow that hit
the center is not mine.
Oh, heavens!
Whose is it?
I can't make out who it is.
I'll go see.
Go, Opal!
He left some directions.
Hello, Sapphire!
Show yourself!
- Prince Frank!
- Sorry about that arrow,
but I wanted to see you
without other people around
Today you seem more than ever
in an excellent mood, Princess!
I already told you
that I am not a Princess!
- I am a Prince!
- No one can hear us,
so there is no need to
hide the truth, Princess.
how do I have to tell you
that I am a boy?!
Absolutely a boy!
Now listen, take this
This is a pen! Why did you give it
to me? What do you want me to do with it?
You've got the pen.
Now I will give you the ink.
Since you claim
to be a boy,
be so kind as
to put it in writing for me.
For what reason should I do it?
That pen, in reality,
is a magic pen.
Do as I told you!
"I declare that Prince Sapphire
is a boy".
Do you think you wrote
that Sapphire is a boy?
Reread carefully
what you wrote.
"Sapphire is a girl"... Eh?!
Did you see? You yourself wrote
that you are a girl!
How strange! And yet I'm sure I
wrote that I am a boy.
I'll try again.
"Sapphire is a boy".
"Sapphire is a girl"
But I didn't write
that I am a girl!
The sentence changed by itself.
Sapphire, that pen, in reality,
is a magic pen.
You cannot write
false things with this pen.
No matter how well one can lie,
the pen writes the truth.
You know, Sapphire,
I like you a lot.
And you are also very kind.
Not only are you kind,
but you are also very generous
...and you go out of your way for your friends:
you have great goodness of heart.
Now, Sapphire, I would like to ask
of your generosity...
...a big favor:
can you give the magic pen..
...to that girl
with the long, brown hair?
You know, the one I met
at that carnival party...
...and with whom I danced
the whole evening!
Why do you want me to give the pen
to that girl?
I would like to know what she thinks of me.
I can't forget her.
I will never forget
that time I danced...
..with that girl
with long hair.
Oh, Franz! I wish I could tell you that
in reality that girl is me.
Please, Sapphire,
search in your kingdom..
...the girl
with long brown hair
...and tell her to write me
a letter with this pen.
You could go ask him
yourself.
No, I can't. My father
almost never lets me go out.
Today I snuck out.
Prince Franz!
Your father noticed
that you weren't at the castle...
...and ordered us to search for you.
Please, Your Highness,
return to the castle now,
your father will be furious.
I had something to do,
that's why I went out.
So, Sapphire, please,
do what I told you.
Goodbye!
Welcome back to the castle, Prince!
But where are you?
Have you hidden yourself?
You don't want to be found, eh?
I get it:
you are in the secret room!
You want to wear a dress
as a girl today, right?
It's natural,
since in reality you are!
I wonder if Franz, one day,
will understand the truth...!
Now I'll have to write him a letter
"I am the girl
with long brown hair"
Strange, the pen moved
by itself! Let's see what it wrote.
"The true identity of the girl
with brown hair is Sapphire.
" Oh, no! I can't send
him a letter like that!
Good grief, this really is
a magic pen!
It makes people express
what they really think.
Here is my nursemaid!
Hey!
Have you pulled another
of your tricks? What is this?
Try writing
everything you think of me.
Here!
"Prince Sapphire is always so
mischievous and impertinent...
...that sometimes I
hate him!" There you go!
"I hope Prince Sapphire
will grow up healthy."
Thank you very much, nurse!
What?!
You must write
what you think of me.
Yes, sir! "Prince Sapphire
is a wonderful Prince,
like no other in the whole
world! Long live Prince Sapphire!
Long live the Prince of Silverland!"
"Now I would like a hot chocolate,
an orange soda, and an ice cream."
You're very hungry, aren't you?
Who will be next?
Oh, I'm so sorry!
Good heavens, Prince Sapphire!
We must be considerate
of animals!
Look how beautiful
this bird is.
It doesn't deserve
to be harmed.
You are right! So as not to forget
your words,
- please write them here
- Of course, Prince!
Now then... "We must not
harm animals."
There we go!
"I will kill this peacock..
...and decorate the hut
with its feathers"? That's impossible!
But how did I manage
to write this?!
Knowing the truth from
people is very interesting.
Yes, because many people
are so sly...
Here is Nylon! I would
like to know what he thinks!
Good morning, Prince!
What can I do for you?
What do you think of when you see me?
What do I think of you? That I
am happy to see you doing well...
...and to see you grow strong and
healthy, because you must become King.
Thank you, Nylon, but now
write these words up here.
I will do as you wish! I will write down
for you everything that is on my mind.
Come here, you big peacock! Stop!
I need your feathers
for my hairstyle! Stop!
Honestly! Stop
Oh, excuse me, Prince Sapphire!
Excuse me!
What is going on?
"I am sure that Sapphire
is a girl.
One day I will find out the truth"
I didn't write
such a terrible thing!
"Tonight, at midnight"... Here
you stopped writing, Nylon.
- Well, I...
- What do you want to do at midnight?
Come on, tell me!
I don't know! Let me go!
I don't know anything!
Wait!
- Wait for me! Wait!
- No! No, I'm not waiting for you! No!
I told you to wait!
Will you stop?!
Where are you going?
Fortunately I didn't write
what will happen at midnight!
Welcome, Prince Sapphire!
Grand Duke Duralumin, what are you to do
tonight, at midnight?
Write the answer up here!
Excuse me, Prince, I prefer
to answer in words.
With words, it's easier
to lie. Write it down!
I really can't.
See? My hand is injured.
Write with your left hand.
My left hand is injured too, so
there is no other solution left...
...but to talk about it.
- I won't listen to your lies.
See you later, Grand Duke!
You did well, because that
magic pen is truly terrible!
No, that pen is wonderful!
With it, not even Sapphire
will be able to write a lie.
You'll see: I will manage to make
him write that, in reality, he is a girl.
I understand! That
seems like a great idea!
Anyway, what do we do
with tonight's plan?
The plan? We'll carry it out!
It will be interesting!
There's an hour left until midnight.
I hope I can manage to stay awake.
I thought I heard a noise!
My eyes are closing.
I fell asleep!
But this is a fire!
It won't open!
I have to open it somehow!
Help! There's a fire!
With the firefighters
the flames don't last long!
It seems like they
were waiting for the fire.
Fire, we do not fear
you! We master the fires!
What are you doing?!
Throw some water on it!
- Don't worry!
- You give us the job!
And we put out the fire!
They don't have water with them
and they are pretending to be busy.
With us, the fire doesn't last long!
Without water,
you can't be firefighters!
Prince, remember: if you
obstruct us, you will be punished!
Scoundrels! I have realized
that you are fake firefighters!
If you don't let us work, you
will see the castle in ashes!
The fire is growing!
And now...
That's enough! Go away!
Prince, leave it alone!
This could split your head open!
Scoundrels! It was you
who set fire to the castle!
You did it on purpose, didn't you?
Help! Fire!
I'm coming with water!
Will I tame the fire?
Come on, pump the water!
Come on! Here it is, finally!
Here it is, Your Highness!
Thank you, Garigori.
What is it?
Don't run away! Stop!
- Let me go, Prince!
- If you tell me who sent you!
I can't say! Give me paper
and a pen and I will write his name!
I'll give him the magic pen..
Here is pen and paper! Now write!
I've got it!
I took the magic pen!
Stop!
You did well!
Sometimes you are useful.
Thank you!
Now we have Sapphire in our grasp
I will not fail to discover her
secret. Very well! Very well!
This time, dear Prince,
it's over for you.
Tink! Where am I?
This is Garigori's room.
First I came to you and saw
that you were fighting with three fake firefighters.
Then you fainted,
so I brought you here
And so you took care of me?
Yes.
Thank you, Tink. I wonder if
my secret room is safe..!
Yes, it is safe, don't worry.
No one will find it.
- I'm sleepy..
- Damn, the pen!
Where could that thief have gone?
Sapphire, where is the pen? You kept
Franz's pen, right?
Yes, I had it, but I lost it
last night, during the fire.
A real mess...
I absolutely must find it!
What's going on?
Where could they be taking
all these tables and chairs?
But Prince!
Excuse me, may I know
what you are preparing?
Your Highness, I don't know the
details, but I heard that this stuff...
...is for the ceremony
of your oath.
My oath?! But what ceremony
are you talking about?
Oh, I don't know, sir.
Well, I really don't know
what it is about, Prince,
but I know that the senior members
of the Council have been summoned,
so it must certainly be
something important,
even though I don't have the slightest idea
of what is brewing...
and I'd really like to know.
Prince Sapphire! The Grand Duke
and the members of the Council...
...are waiting for you
in the ceremony hall.
Really? For what?
He only told me
to accompany you there
I see.
I'm coming right away.
Welcome to the Council Chamber,
Prince.
What does this ceremony mean?
And also, I would like you to explain to me
why I must take an oath!
You see, someone has doubts
about your identity, and so...
It's a very simple ceremony,
Your Highness.
- And what should I do?
- It's very simple:
you only have to write
on this paper...
...that you swear to be
the Prince of this kingdom...
...and that you will always behave
like a true Prince. That's all.
Now we will give you the pen
to write these things.
- It's the magic pen!
- What is the matter, Your Highness?
I will not write that oath!
I have no intention of doing so!
Prince, His Majesty the King
has approved this oath.
..and has affixed the seal
of his consent!
Even if you do not want to, we will make you
do it against your will.
So, are you determined to write
that sentence?
No, I will not write with that pen
otherwise I would write
that Sapphire is a girl
Wait,
consult Prince Franz.
- He might have some idea.
- Too late.
Still, it's worth a try!
I'm rushing to his palace!
Wait, Tink! It's no use!
He won't make it in time.
The ceremony will begin in an hour.
- The ceremony begins.
- Get out of the way!
Prince, the time has come!
Follow me
to the Hall of Ceremonies!
Prince, please, sit down
on that chair, please.
No!
Sapphire, what's wrong?
You shouldn't refuse
to go to write this oath.
- Excuse me, but...
- What is happening, Your Highness?
You seem extremely embarrassed.
Sapphire,
go and sit down immediately
Have you made up your mind? Here is the pen
What can be done? Sapphire must
write the oath immediately.
Sapphire, you cannot back out.
You must sign in front of everyone.
Oh, no!
Faster, eagles!
Faster!
Fly faster!
Let's hurry!
There's no time to lose!
There it is, the castle!
Eagles,
fly towards that window!
Tink, jump! Come on!
Please, eagles,
get closer!
Well, make up your mind,
Prince Sapphire?
Do you have any reason
to refuse to write?
If you really are not a girl,
you have no reason to hesitate.
Sapphire has already taken
that pen in hand!
- What?! She's lost!
- Not yet,
if you quickly come up with
some good idea!
We must try to save him
at all costs!
I can't think of any ideas,
but if I could manage to drop in there...
Yes, do it, please!
- Wait!
- Where is this troublemaker?
Cut, Tink!
Franz!
My name is Franz! I travel around the
entire world to fight!
I came here to measure myself
against Prince Sapphire,
- given his fame!
- Damn troublemaker!
Soldiers, arrest that man!
- Come on, Sapphire!
- All right, Franz! Here I am!
Anyone who interrupts this
fight will be punished!
Damned boy! Did he
have to arrive right now?
On guard, Franz!
- How are you, Princess?
- I am very grateful to you, Franz.
- To you!
- Well done!
Follow me, quickly! Let's
go! Pretend to chase me!
Wait!
Take this! Take this!
Well done! Hooray!
Now Sapphire is safe!
I can sleep peacefully!
I was very worried about
what could happen to me.
I'm really sorry. From now on,
I won't use this pen anymore.
Franz, I think there
is a big difference...
...between what is said
and what is thought.
Yeah. I wonder if the girl
with the brown hair...
...will tell me the truth...
I really think she will tell you.
I am certain
that you will meet again soon
What?! Is it true? Seriously?
He still doesn't realize
the truth.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP